Inventaris van het archief van het Institute of Social Studies, 1952-2009
Nationaal Archief, Den Haag
- Instandhouding van de organisatie, B.
  - Huisvesting, B.3
    - Ontruimingsplan Kortenaerkade 12 Den Haag, 1995; 526; 1 stuk
  - Financiën, B.4
    - Probleemanalyse inzake de kostenstructuur van extern gefinancierde projecten van het Institute of Social Studies / P.J. Klerk; BSO advies., 1992; 527; 1 omslag
      Met bijlagen
    - Stukken betreffende de financiële situatie van het ISS, 1994; 528; 1 omslag
      Bevat: The Financial Situation of the ISS: a Critical Analysis / prepared by an Ad-hoc committee of the Institute Council
    - Report Financial Mechanisms Committee, 1996; 529; 1 omslag
    - Diversificatie van financiering: Van denken naar doen / Stichting DFW, 2001; 530; 1 omslag
    - Budget procedures and guidelines / Deputy rector/office of management and budget, 2000; 531; 1 omslag
    - Jaarrekeningen, 1988 - 2008; 532-536; 1 omslag, 18 delen
      - 1988 - 1989, 532
        met bijlage
      - 1991 - 1994, 533
        1992 draft; 1994 met bijlagen
      - 1995 - 1999, 534
      - 2000 - 2002, 535
      - 2003 - 2008, 536
    - Accountants verklaringen 1985, 1987 - 1989, 1993 - 1995, 2001, 2004, 1987- 2005; 537; 1 omslag
    - Begrotingen/budgets, 1972 - 2008; 538-543; 6 omslagen
      - 1972 - 1980, 1971 - 1979, 538
        concept van 1978 bevindt zich in band inv.nr. 40
      - 1981 - 1984, 1986 - 1991, 1980 - 1990, 539
      - Budget 1991-1993, 1991 - 1993, 540
      - Budget 1994 en 1995, 1994 - 1995, 541
      - Budget 1996-2002,1995 - 2001, 542
      - Budget 2003-2009, 2002 - 2008, 543
  - Bibliotheek en IT Services, B.5
    - Verslagen en agenda’s van vergaderingen van de bibliotheekcommissie, 1967 - 1976; 544-546; 3 omslagen
      - 1967 - 1971, 544
      - 1972 - 1974, 545
      - 1975 - 1976, 546
    - Stukken over de bibliotheek van het ISS door Jacob N. van der Vlugt (bibliothecaris), 1962; 547; 1 omslag
    - Rapportages over het bibliotheek- en documentatieprogramma van ISS aan de Ford Foundation New York, 1965 - 1968; 548; 1 omslag
    - Jaarverslagen 1994-1998, 2000, 2002,2004, 1995 - 2005; 549; 1 omslag
    - Beleidsplannen, 1978 - 2000; 550; 1 omslag
    - Folders, 1995, 2005 - 2009; 551; 1 omslag
  - Marketing en Communicatie, B.6
    - Stukken betreffende marketing en communicatie, 1984 - 2005; 552; 1 omslag
    - Development ISSues, 1999 - 2009; 553-554; 2 omslagen
      Opvolger van ISS bulletin en Alumni Magazine. Fungeert als platform voor informatie uitwisseling tussen het ISS en haar internationale netwerk. Verschijnt 3 keer per jaar
      - Vol. 1, nr. 1 1999 - Vol. 4, nr. 3 2002, 553
      - Vol. 5, nr. 1 2003 - Vol. 11, nr. 2 2009, 554
    - Stukken betreffende ISS representatives, 1998 - 2001; 555; 1 omslag
    - Reconsidering strategy and internal organisation of the ISS: report on development of an ISS business plan for the acquisition of external funds / PriceWaterhouseCoopers, oktober 1998; 556; 1 omslag
    - Stukken betreffende fondsenwerving, oktober 1998 - januari 2006; 557; 1 omslag
    - Training programma voor TPG Post, 2003; 558; 1 omslag
    - Huisstijl: folders, posters etc., 1979 - 2009; 559-561; 3 omslagen
      - 1979 - 1990, 559
      - 1990 - 2000, 560
      - 2000 - 2009, 561
  - Publications Committee, B.7
    - Jaarrapporten, 1984 - 1997; 562-563; 2 omslagen
      1987 en 1990 ontbreken
      - 1984 - 1989, 562
      - 1991 - 1997, 563
    - Stukken betreffende het publiceren van boeken bij het ISS, 1973 - 1998; 564; 1 omslag
- Taakuitoefening, C.
  - Onderwijs, C.1
    - Onderwijsbeleid, C.1.1
      - Discussienota over plaats en toekomst van het ISS in het internationaal onderwijs, 1986; 565; 1 omslag
        Met bijlagen. Nota ook in Engelstalige versie.
      - Stukken betreffende de positie van het ISS in Nederlands bestel van Hoger Onderwijs, 1987 - 1993; 566-567; 2 omslagen
        Zie ook inv.nrs. erkenning MA
        - 1987 - 1989, 566
        - 1990 - 1993, 567
          Bevat stukken commissie Wolfson
      - On the improvement of the quality of teaching at the ISS, 1998; 568; 1 stuk
      - Teaching strategy / Office of Educational Affairs, 2004 - 2005; 569; 1 omslag
      - Learning to change the world?: towards critically teaching critical social science / Robert Ensor, juni 2005; 570; 1 stuk
      - Professorial/UHD plan, 1993 - 1998, 2001; 571-572; 1 omslag, 1 deel
        - 1993 - 1998, 571; 1 omslag
          Met commentaren en voorstellen. Bevat drafts.
        - 2002 - 2006, 572; 1 deel
      - Stukken betreffende het promotierecht van ISS professoren, 1994 - 1998; 573; 1 omslag
    - Onderwijsorganisatie, C.1.2
      - Rules and regulations in the field of teaching, 1983; 574; 1 stuk
      - Rules and regulations concerning teaching and student affairs, 1998 - 2001; 575-577; 3 delen
        - 1998 - 1999, 575
        - 1999 - 2000, 576
        - 2000 - 2001, 577
      - Toekomst Onderwijsorganisatie, 1991 - 1995; 578; 1 omslag
        Bevat TAFTE en TOMATO report
      - Reorganisatie van de onderwijs organisatie, 1996; 579; 1 omslag
        Bevat Report academic priority committee, sept 1996
      - Stafgroep formatie, 1997; 580; 1 omslag
      - Verslagen en agenda’s en stukken van bijeenkomsten van de stafgroep besturen, 1998 - 2009; 581-582; 2 omslagen
        - 1998, 581
        - 1999 - 2009, 582
      - Verslagen, agenda’s van vergaderingen en stukken van Stafgroep 1 (Economics of sustainable development), 1999 - 2004; 583
        Met hiaten
      - Stukken betreffende Stafgroep 2 (States, Society, World Development), 1999 - 2007; 584
        Stukken uit 2001, 2003 en 2004 ontbreken
      - Stukken betreffende Stafgroep 3 (Human resources and local development), oktober 1998 - 2007; 585
      - Stukken betreffende Stafgroep 4 (Rural development, environment and population studies), aug 1998 - april 2006; 586
        met hiaten
      - Profielen van leerstoelen, 1974, 1998 - 2004; 587-588; 2 omslagen
        - 1974, 587
        - 1998 - 2004, 588
      - Stukken over de uitbesteding uitvoeringstaken Nederlands Fellowship Programma (NFP), 1986 - 2002; 589-592; 4 omslagen
        - 1986 - 1987, 589
        - 1988 - 1990, 590
        - 1991 - 1994, 591
        - 1996 - 2002, 592
      - Stukken betreffende klacht/geschil inzake programma Employment and Labour Studies (ELS), 1994; 593; 1 omslag
      - Stukken betreffende conflict ELS, 1995; 594; 1 omslag
      - Correspondentie betreffende problemen Centre for Resource Studies for Development (CERES) en ELS, 1995; 595; 1 omslag
      - Advisory Committee ELS, 1995 - 1996; 596; 1 omslag
        Bevat het uiteindelijke adviesrapport.
      - Correspondentie Spoor/Thomas, Boelman/Thomas, 1995; 597; 1 omslag
    - Onderwijsevaluatie, C.1.3
      - Stukken betreffende de evaluatie van programma’s, 1982 - 1988, 2003 - 2004; 598; 1 omslag
      - Stukken betreffende de evaluatie van Development, Law, Social Justice en Human Rights programme, 599-602; 4 omslagen
        - 1986 - 1997, 599
        - 1998, 600
        - 1999, 601
        - 2000 - 2003, 602
      - Teaching Progress reports, 1995 - 2004; 603-604; 2 omslagen
        - 1995 - 1999, 603
        - 2000 - 2005, 604
          2005 is een concept
      - External examiner’s reports, 1999 - 2006; 605; 1 omslag
      - MA Programme in development studies: report of a review team, 2001 - 2002; 606; 1 omslag
      - Self-assessment report M.A. in development studies, 2005; 607; 1 omslag
      - "The article 218" status and the quality of the ISS master programme / by Boem van Ravenswaaij, mei 1988; 608; 1 omslag
      - Stukken van de Task Force on Evaluation of Teaching, 1988 - 1990; 609; 1 omslag
      - Stukken betreffende onderwijsevaluatie en visitatie, december 1991 - november 2000; 610-611; 2 omslagen
        - december 1991-februari 1998, 610
        - maart 1998-november 2000, 611
      - Self study, 1996, 1998; 612; 1 omslag
      - Reviews of the ISS, 1997 - 1998; 613; 1 omslag
      - The CERC Report, 1998; 614; 1 omslag
      - Leergang evaluaties, 2004 - 2007; 615; 1 omslag
    - Studieprogramma's, C.1.4
      - Diploma programs, C.1.4.1
        - Reports on Diploma Courses, 1962, 1963, 1965; 616; 1 omslag
        - International Relations and Development (IRD) diploma programme, 1987 - 1988; 617; 1 omslag
        - Rules and regulations concerning diploma programmes teaching and student affairs, 2002 - 2007; 618; 1 omslag
      - MA programme, C.1.4.2
        - Master’s Degree Committee (MDC), maart 1979 - januari 1994; 619; 1 omslag
        - Labour and development four-year activity plan 1983-1986, 620; 1 stuk
        - Erkenning MA opleiding development studies, 1990 - 1994, (1999); 621; 1 omslag
        - Organization of and Procedures of for the Assessment of Participants: Summary of Proposals (Board of Examiners), [1998]; 622; 1 stuk
        - Stukken betreffende ‘Human Rights’ programma, 1989 - 1990; 623; 1 omslag
        - Rules and regulations concerning MA teaching and student affairs, 2001 - 2006; 624; 1 omslag
        - Rules and regulations concerning the MSC programme in development economics 2002-2003, 625; 1 deel
        - Draft Outlines van verschillende MA-programma’s, 2003; 626; 1 omslag
        - Rapporten over de MA course in Population and Development, 1999 - 2000; 627; 1 omslag
      - PhD programme, C.1.4.3
        - Jaarverslagen PhD Committee (PDC), 1997 - 2003; 628; 1 omslag
        - Guides to the ISS PhD programme, 1994 - 1995; 629; 1 omslag
          Contains a supervisor’s guide and a student guide
        - Rules and regulations on the PhD programme and award procedures, 1992 - 2006; 630; 1 omslag
        - Erkenning ISS PhD, 1982, 1992; 631; 1 omslag
      - Refresher courses, C.1.4.4
        - Stukken betreffende Refresher courses, 1993 - 2002; 632; 1 omslag
        - Reports on Refresher Courses, 1993 - 2004; 633-635; 3 pakken
          - 1993 - 1997, 633
          - 1998 - 2000, 634
          - Ca. 2000-2004, 635
    - Cursusaanbod, C.1.5
      - Prospecti, 1953 - 2010; 636-639; 3 omslagen, 1 pak
        1966 ontbreekt
        - 1953-1954 - 1965-1965, 636; 1 omslag
          bevat o.a.: -Two Years’ Course in the Social Sciences Oct. 1956-July 1958, - Six Months Advanced Diploma Course in Economic Planning and Social Accounting, January 7 - July 8, 1957 en - Six Months Advanced Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 7-July 8, 1957.
        - 1967-1970 - 1989-1990, 637; 1 pak
        - 1990-1991 - 1998-1999, 638; 1 omslag
        - 1999-2000 - 2009-2010, 639; 1 omslag
          Bevat: Postgraduate Diploma Programmes 2004
      - Academic Calenders, 640-674
        ontbrekende Calendars zijn eventueel te vinden in de banden van het Curatorium
        - 1955 - juli 1966, 640; 1 pak
          bevat: - Six months’ Advanced Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 10-July 8, 1955 - Two years’ Course in the Social Science, October 1956-July 1958 - Six Months Advanced Diploma Course in Economic Planning and Social Accounting, January 4-July 8, 1957 - Six Months’ Advanced Diploma Course in Public Administration for 1957 - Six-Month Diploma Course in Social Welfare Policy for Low Countries, September 16, 1957-April 3, 1958 - Six-Month Advanced Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 10-July 11, 1958 - Six-Month Diploma Course in Social Welfare Policy for Low-Income Countries, September 1, 1958-March 25, 1959 - Programme Master of Social Science, 1965-1966 - Eight-Month Diploma Course in Social Policy, May – December 1965 - Statistics and National Accounting Course, 1st September, 1965 – 4th March, 1966 Industrial Development Programming Course, September 1 – December 23, 1965 - Advanced Course in Public Administration, August 16, 1965 – July 8, 1966 - National Development Course, September 1, 1965 – July 8, 1966 - International Relations Course, October 8, 1965 – July 8, 1966 - Public Administration Course, January 10 – July 8, 1966 - Economic Planning Course, January 3 – July 8, 1966
        - mei 1966 - juli 1967, 641; 1 pak
          -Eight Month Diploma Course in Social Policy, May-December 1966 -Industrial Development Programming Course, September 1 – December 22, 1966 -Advanced Programme in the Social Sciences, August, 1966 – July, 1967 -Statistics and National Accounting Course, 22nd August, 1966 – 17th February, 1967 -National Development Course, September 5, 1966 – July 7, 1967 -Industrial Development Programming Course, September 5 – December 20, 1967 -Third International Relations Course, October 6, 1966 – July 6, 1967 -Economic Planning Course, January 2, -July 7, 1967 -Public Administration Course, January 9 – July 7, 1967
        - augustus 1967 - juli 1969, 642; 1 pak
          -Advanced Programme in the Social Sciences, August, 1967 – July, 1968 -Statistics and National Accounting Course, 4th September, 1967 – 29th February, 1968 -National Development Course, September 4, 1967 – July 5, 1968 -Eight Month Diploma Course in Social Policy, September 1967 – May 1968 -Fourth International Relations Course, October 5, 1967 – July 5, 1968 -Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 8 – July 5, 1968 -Economic Planning Course, January 4 – July 5, 1968 -Advanced Course in the Social Sciences, August, 1968 – July, 1969 -Statistics and National Accounting course, 2nd September, 1968 – 28th February, 1969 -Eight-Month Diploma Course in Social Policy, September 1968 – May 1969 -Advanced Course in Public Administration, September 2, 1968 – July 5, 1969 -National Development Course, 2nd September, 1968 – 4th July, 1969 -Regional Development Planning Course, October 7, 1968 – July 4, 1969
        - januari 1969 - juni 1970, 643; 1 pak
          -Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 8 – July 4, 1969 --Fifth International Relations Course, January 8, 1969 – July 4, 1969 --Economic Planning Course, January 6 – July 5, 1969 --Industrial Development Programming Course, March 3 – July 2, 1969 --Economic Planning Course, November 3, 1969-May 28, 1970 --Diploma Course in Social Policy: Industrial and Labour Relations, September 1969-May 1970 --Statistics and National Accounting Course, 3rd November-28th May, 1970 --Advanced Course in Public Administration, September 2, 1969-July 10, 1970 --Industrial Development Programming Course, 3rd November, 1969-28th March 1970 --National Development Course, 9th September, 1969-30th June, 1970 --Diploma Course in Social Policy: Social Planning and Community Development, September 1969-May 1970 --Sixth International Relations Course, January 5-June 30, 1970 --Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 5-June 30, 1970
        - september 1970 - juni 1971, 644; 1 pak
          Advanced Course in Public Administration, September 1, 1970-June 30, 1971 -Diploma Course in Social Policy, October 1970-June 1971 -Seventh International Relations Course, October 1, 1970-June 30, 1971 -National Development Course, 1st October, 1970-30th June, 1971 -Regional Development Planning Course, October 1, 1970-June 30, 1971 -Statistics and National Accounting Course, November 2, 1970-May 28, 1971 -Industrial Development Programming Course, 2nd November, 1970-28th March 1971 -Economic Planning Course, November 2, 1970-May 28, 1971 -Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 4-June 30, 1971 -
        - September 1971 - juni 1973, 645; 1 pak
          Advanced Course in Public Administration, September 1, 1971-June 30, 1972 -Regional Development Planning Course, October 1, 1971-June 30, 1972 -Industrial Development Programming Course, 1 November-31 March 1972 -Statistics and National Accounting Course, 1 November 1971-31 May 1972 -Economic Planning Course, 1 November 1971-31 May 1972 -Industrial Relations Course, 1 December 1971-30 May 1972 -Diploma Course in Public Administration, January 3-June 30, 1972 -Postgraduate Diploma Course in Development Administration, October 2, 1972-June 29, 1973 -Workshop on Transformation and Participation Urban Social Development Programme, 5 October 1972-29 June 1973 – Provisional Calendar -Rural Development Programme, October 2, 1972-June 30, 1973 -Workshop on Transformation and Participation Urban Social Development Programme, 5 October 1972-29 June 1973 -Socio-Economic Planning Programme, October 2, 1972-June 30, 1973 -Statistics and National Accounting Programme, October 2, 1972-May 31, 1973 -Regional Development Planning Course, October 2, 1972-June 29, 1973
        - oktober 1973 - maart 1977, 646; 1 pak
          International and National Development Programme, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Industrial Relations Programme, October 1973-June 1974 -Post-Graduate Diploma Programme in Development Administration, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Regional Development Planning Course, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Workshop on Social Organization and Development- Urban Social Development Programme, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Post-Graduate Diploma Programme in Statistics and National Accounting, October 1, 1973-May 31, 1974 -Post-Graduate Diploma Programme in Project Analysis, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Post-Graduate Diploma Programme in Socio-Economic Planning, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Workshop on Social Organization and Development- Urban Social Development Programme, October 1, 1973-June 28, 1974 -Development Planning Workshop Post Graduate Diploma Programmes in Socio-Economic Planning Project Analysis Statistical & National Accounting, October 1, 1974-June 30, 1975 -Development Administration Workshop Post-Graduate Diploma Programme in Development Administration, October 1, 1974-June 30, 1975 -Development Administration Workshop Post Graduate Diploma Programmes in Development Administration, October 1, 1975-June 30, 1976 -Development Planning Workshop Post Graduate Diploma Programmes in Socio-Economic Planning Project Analysis Statistics & National Accounting, October 1, 1975-June 30, 1976 -Social Organization and Development Workshop Post Graduate Diploma Programmes in Urban Social Development Rural Development Industrial Relations and Labour Studies, October 1, 1975-June 30, 1976 -Development Planning Workshop Post- Graduate Diploma Programme in Project Analysis, October 4, 1976-June 24, 1977 -Development Planning Workshop Post Graduate Diploma Programme in Statistics & National Accounting, October 4, 1976-May 27, 1977 -Urban Social Development Programme, October 11, 1976-March 31, 1977 -
        - 1977-1978 - 1979-1980, 647; 1 pak
          Academic Year 1977-1978 -General Information on Academic Programmes 1979-1980-Academic Calendar 1979-1980 Master Degree in Development Studies -Academic Calendar 1979-1980 Diploma Programmes,-
        - 1980-1981 - 1981-1982, 648; 1 pak
          -Academic Calendar 1980-1981 Master Degree in Development Studies-Academic Calendar 1980-1981 Diploma Programmes-General Information on Academic Programmes 1981-1982 -Academic calendar 1981-1982 Master Degree in Development Studies -Academic Calendar 1981-1982 Diploma Programmes -Diploma Programme in International Communications -Diploma Programme in Communication Policy and planning for Development, June 7-July 30, 1982
        - 1982-1983 - 1983-1984, 649; 1 pak
          General Information on Academic Programmes 1982-1983 -Academic Calendar 1982-1983 Master Degree in Development Studies -Academic Calendar 1982-1983 Diploma Programmes -Diploma Programme Communications Policy and Planning Development, Kenya, 1983 -Development, Law and Social Justice. A special Experimental Programme, April 27-June 18, 1983 -Academic Calendar 1983-1984 Master Degree in Development Studies -Academic Calendar 1983-1984 Diploma Programmes
        - 1984, 650; 1 omslag
          Diploma Programme Communications Policy and Planning Development, Kenya 1984 -General information on academic programmes 1984-85 -Academic calendar 84-85 Master’s degree in development studies -Academic calendar 84-85 Diploma programmes
        - 1985, 651; 1 omslag
          General information on Academic Programmes 85-86 -Academic calendar 85-86. Master of arts in development studies -Academic calendar 85-86. Diploma Programmes
        - 1986, 652; 1 omslag
          Academic calendar 86-87 Master of arts in development studies -Academic calendar 86-87 diploma programmes
        - 1987 - 1988, 653; 1 omslag
          General information on academic programmes 87-88 -Academic calendar 87-88 Master of arts in development studies -Academic calendar 87-88 diploma programmes -Development, Law and Social Justice: a special teaching programme on human rights, april 13-June 3, 1988 -
        - 1988 - 1989, 654; 1 omslag
          General information on academic programmes 88-89 -Academic calendar 88-89 Master of arts in development studies -Academic calendar 88-89 diploma programmes -Academic calendar 88-89 general courses -Development. Law and social justice: a special teaching programme on human rights, april 12-June 2, 1989
        - 1989 - 1990, 655; 1 omslag
          General information on academic programmes 1989-90+ -MA Development Studies 1989-1990 +Economic Policy and Planning -Politics of alternative development strategies -Labour and development -+Regional development planning -+Agricultural and rural development -+Women and development -+Public policy and Administration -Diploma programmes 1989-1990+ -+Population and development -+Development planning techniques -+International Law and organization for development -+Rural policy and project planning -Development. Law and social justice: a special teaching programme on human rights, april 18-June 8, 1990 +
        - 1990 - 1991, 656; 1 omslag
          General information on Academic Programmes 1990-91 -Academic calendar 90-91 General Courses -Sub-specializations on offer -MA Development Studies 1990-1991 -+Economic Policy and Planning -+Labour and Development -+Politics of alternative development strategies -+Regional development planning -+Agricultural and rural development -+Women and development -+Public policy and Administration -Diploma Programmes 1990-1991 -+Population and development -+Development planning techniques -+International Law and organization for development -+International relations and development -+Rural policy and project planning -Development. Law and Social Justice: a special teaching programme on Human Rights, april 29-June 19, 1991
        - 1991 - 1992, 657; 1 omslag
          General information on academic programmes 1991-92 -Sub-Specializations on Offer Academic Year 1991-1992 -MA Development Studies 1991-1992 +Economic Policy and Planning -+Labour and Development -+Politics of alternative development strategies -+Regional development planning -+Agricultural and rural development -+Women and development -+Public policy and Administration -Diploma Programmes 1991-1992 -+Population and development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+International Relations and Development -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+Development Planning Techniques -Development. Law and Social Justice: a Special Teaching Programme on Human Rights, April 23-June 17, 1992
        - 1992 - 1993, 658; 1 omslag
          MA Development Studies 1992-1993 -+Economic Policy and Planning -+Labour and Development -+Politics of Alternative Development Strategies -+Agricultural and Rural Development -+Regional Development Planning -+Women and Development -+Public Policy and Administration -+Sub-Specializations 1992-1993 -Diploma Programmes 1992-1993 -+Population and Development -+Development Planning Techniques -+International Law and Organization for Development -+International Relations and Development -+Rural Policy and Project Planning
        - 1993 - 1994, 659; 1 omslag